<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Glossary : Seismic Interferometry</title>
    <link>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/index.html</link>
    <description>This glossary contains definitions for terms that may be commonly understood by students from either an earth science or a physics background, but that may not be widely used in both. To request any other words be added to this glossary, email me here.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 16:30:28 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Attenuation</title>
      <link>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/attenuation/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 16:30:28 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/attenuation/index.html</guid>
      <description>The attenuation of a signal is the reduction of its intensity as it travels. This may be due to absorption in the medium or deflection/scattering on the particles within the medium. The final signal then has less magnitude than when it was produced.1&#xA;(McKetty, 1998) ↩︎</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Borehole</title>
      <link>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/borehole/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 16:30:16 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/borehole/index.html</guid>
      <description>Boreholes are wells or test holes drilled into the ground for geological investigations. Different probes can be lowered into these boreholes to gather information such as lithology, density, permeability and porosity, water quality, electric and thermal conductivity, radioactivity, and magnetisation.1 One of their benefits is in allowing multiple readings to be taken under the same conditions, allowing easy combination and comparison of data.2&#xA;(Roach, 2024) ↩︎&#xA;(New York Water Science Center, 2018) ↩︎</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlation and Convolution</title>
      <link>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/correlation-and-convolution/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 16:30:03 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/correlation-and-convolution/index.html</guid>
      <description>Correlation and Convolution are two operations that can be taken on functions, using Fourier techniques. A convolution can be written as:&#xA;\[f(t) = g(t) * h(t) = \int^\infty_{-\infty} g(\tau) h(t - \tau) d\tau \] With dummy variable $\tau$. In Fourier (frequency) space, a convolution can be written as:&#xA;\[ F(\omega) = G(\omega)H(\omega) \] A correlation on the other hand can be written as:&#xA;\[ f(t) = g(-t) * h(t) = \int^\infty_{-\infty} g(\tau + t) h(t) d\tau \] Or in Fourier space:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fourier Transform</title>
      <link>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/fourier-transform/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 16:29:49 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/fourier-transform/index.html</guid>
      <description>A Fourier transform is a mathematical technique that transforms data collected over time (or space) to temporal (or spatial) frequency data, with an inverse Fourier transform doing the reverse. For example, a cosine wave with frequency $\omega$ could be detected at a receiver over a recording period of 20 seconds. Taking the Fourier transform of this data will produce a frequency spectrum with two delta spikes (peaks), at $\omega$ and $-\omega$ (see the diagram below1).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geophone</title>
      <link>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/geophone/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 16:29:36 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/geophone/index.html</guid>
      <description>Geophones are ground motion sensors, typically used for detecting high frequency (4Hz-400Hz) seismic waves. These devices, which are cheap and have been used by geophysicists for decades, convert the ground motion generated by the seismic waves into a voltage, typically using a magnet inside a spring-braced coil, hence having an output proportional to the instrument velocity. Newer devices have instead used micromachined accelerometers to the same end.1&#xA;(Barzilai, 2009) ↩︎</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greens Function</title>
      <link>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/greens-function/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 16:29:26 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/greens-function/index.html</guid>
      <description>A Green’s function is a system’s response to an impulsive point source.1 That is, it is the influence of a point source at one given location or time, on a different location or time. Mathematically, it can be found as G in:&#xA;\[ L u(x) = f(x) \] \[ u(x) = \int_\Omega G(x, y) f(y) dy \] With $u(x)$ as the response at x to source function $f(x)$ with domain $\Omega$, with y a dummy integration variable and L a linear differential operator (basically just meaning the left hand side of the first equation is some differential equation).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redatum</title>
      <link>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/redatum/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 16:29:09 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/redatum/index.html</guid>
      <description>Redatuming data is a numerical process, moving seismic sources or receivers from their initial acquisition positions, into virtual locations from their reflectivity history / potential. This process can simplify the seismic signals, if the receiver is redatumed to beneath a complex overburden, for example. Traditionally the process was completed using velocity distribution models, which limited its accuracy. Seismic interferometry innovates on this, relying only on recorded wave data (including higher-order reflections), which can then be correlated and summed over in order to determine more reliable experimental results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reservoir</title>
      <link>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/reservoir/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 16:28:56 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/reservoir/index.html</guid>
      <description>Reservoirs are geological features that capture water, oil, gas, or other fluid substances in their structures. These are typically areas of high porosity and low permeability, such that the fluid can accumulate in their pore spaces, but they remain predominantly solid rock. They are of significant interest to groundwater investigators and exploration geologists.1&#xA;(Zhang, 2022) ↩︎</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teleseisms</title>
      <link>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/teleseisms/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 16:28:43 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/glossary/teleseisms/index.html</guid>
      <description>Teleseismic signals are those generated from sources (typically earthquakes) at large distances to the receiver. These signals are typically quite low frequency (to the point that many sensors may be unable to sense any but the largest teleseismic signals), and arrive somewhat close to vertically at the surface receiver locations (being more vertical when they are more distant).1&#xA;(Nazareth and Clayton, 2003) ↩︎</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>