<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>What Is Interferometry? : Seismic Interferometry</title>
    <link>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/what-is-interferometry/index.html</link>
    <description>This section contains a general overview of the basic principles of interferometry, as well as a demonstration of it using an optical interferometer device. The key differences between this demonstration and the seismic interferometry discussed on the rest of this website are also outlined.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 12:59:16 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/what-is-interferometry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/what-is-interferometry/seismic-vs-optical-interferometry/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 12:59:16 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/what-is-interferometry/seismic-vs-optical-interferometry/index.html</guid>
      <description>Interferometry, as a technique, refers to getting information from the interference between two recorded wave signals, normally generated from a single source event. Typically, interferometry is able to measure properties with much more precision than standard wave signal measurements from a single event.1 This is due to it relying on a comparison of phases between the two signals, rather than needing precise knowledge of the start and end forms of the signal (information sometimes referred to as “statics”).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical Example</title>
      <link>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/what-is-interferometry/practical-example/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 12:58:52 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/what-is-interferometry/practical-example/index.html</guid>
      <description>Info&#xD;This practical example aims to highlight how interfering two wave signals can amplify information regarding the difference in paths between the two signals. It uses the easy visualisation opportunities provided by working with visible light to demonstrate this. Here, the information is the difference in path length, but this does not have to be the case for interferometry, as discussed in the general overview.&#xA;Michelson interferometers To understand the physical principles behind interferometry, waves must be recognised as objects with phases attached to them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seismic vs Optical Interferometry</title>
      <link>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/what-is-interferometry/overview/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 12:58:30 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cuttlefish-joe.github.io/what-is-interferometry/overview/index.html</guid>
      <description>The most apparent difference between the optical interferometry demonstrated in this section and the seismic interferometry focussed on by the rest of this website is the type of wave being investigated; optical interferometry uses electromagnetic waves while seismic waves are mechanical/acoustic. While the optical waves can be easily visualised directly (making them good for demonstrations of the concept), the seismic waves must be recorded and processed for visualisation. Additionally, while electromagnetic waves can travel without a medium, the propagation of seismic waves is always tied to the medium being travelled through.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>